Preliminary Inventory of the Lee Edwards Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Sound recordings (Box 1, 8-11, 152-153, 163, 213-221, 330)
  - Lee Edwards interviews Ben Bradlee on 9 October 1992, 1 sound cassette (Box 221)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0009297
  - Lee Edwards interviews Carl Curtis on 4 February 1993, 1 sound cassette (Box 221)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0009312
  - Lee Edwards interviews Dan Popes on 10 December 1992, 1 sound cassette (Box 221)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0009302
  - Lee Edwards interviews Ed Derwinski on 7 May 1993, 1 sound cassette (Box 221)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0009344
  - Lee Edwards interviews Forrest McDonald on 3 April 1993, 1 sound cassette (Box 221)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0009327
  - Lee Edwards interviews George Reedy on 15 February 1993, 1 sound cassette (Box 221)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0009316
    This interview is about the 1964 presidential election with analysis of both Goldwater and Johnson.
  - Lee Edwards interviews Glenn Campbell on 9 January 1993, 1 sound cassette (Box 221)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0009306
  - Lee Edwards interviews Hugh Newton on 26 May 1993, 1 sound cassette (Box 221)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0009348
  - Lee Edwards interviews Jack Buttram on 12 February 1993, 1 sound cassette (Box 221)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0009313
    This interview is about Barry Goldwater with an emphasis on the 1964 campaign.
  - Lee Edwards interviews James Locher on 2 October 1992, 1 sound cassette (Box 221)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0009296
    This interview is about the Goldwater-Nichols Act.
  - Lee Edwards interviews John Warner on 16 February 1993, 1 sound cassette (Box 221)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0009319
  - Lee Edwards interviews Judy Lewis on 29 April 1993, 1 sound cassette (Box 221)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0009340
  - Lee Edwards interviews Margita White on 5 March 1993, 1 sound cassette (Box 221)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0009320
  - Lee Edwards interviews Pat Buchanan on 5 May 1993, 1 sound cassette (Box 221)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0009343
    This interview is about Barry Goldwater, Richard Nixon, and conservative politics.
  - Lee Edwards interviews Peggy Goldwater Clay on 26 April 1993, 1 sound cassette (Box 221)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0009334
  - Lee Edwards interviews Pierre Salinger on 4 February 1993, 1 sound cassette (Box 221)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0009309
  - Lee Edwards interviews Richard Herman on 26 April 1993, 1 sound cassette (Box 221)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0009335
    This interview is about Barry Goldwater. Herman sees the senator as a "progressive conservative," as someone that want to see the government help the individual person help themselves.
  - Lee Edwards interviews Richard Ware on 25 January 1993, 1 sound cassette (Box 221)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0009307
    This interview was conducted by telephone.
  - Lee Edwards interviews Rita Bree on 10 May 1993, 1 sound cassette (Box 221)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0009347
  - Lee Edwards interviews Robert McNeil on 8 March 1993, 1 sound cassette (Box 221)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0009322
  - Lee Edwards interviews Sandra Day O'Connor on 16 June 1993, 1 sound cassette (Box 221)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0009353
  - Lee Edwards interviews Susan Goldwater on 4 January 1993, 1 sound cassette (Box 221)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0009305
  - Lee Edwards interviews Ted Stevens on 25 September 1992, 1 sound cassette (Box 221)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0009293
    This interview concerns Senator Barry Goldwater with an emphasis on his early public career in Washington.
  - Lee Edwards interviews Theodore Sorensen on 8 March 1993, 1 sound cassette (Box 221)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0009321
  - Lee Edwards interviews Tom Phillips on 11 June 1993, 1 sound cassette (Box 221)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0009352
  - Lee Edwards interviews Trent Lott on 22 March 1993, 1 sound cassette (Box 221)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0009325
  - Lee Edwards interviews Virginia Kadell on 11 April 1993, 1 sound cassette (Box 221)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0009328
  - Milton Friedman speech on why he is not a conservative, 1 sound cassette (Box 221)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0009301
    Friedman speaks as part of a Cato Institute event at the Sheraton-Palace Hotel in San Francisco. He highlights that he, Hayek, and Gary Becker are liberals--not conservatives. Calling it a far better statement than his speech, he quotes parts of Hayek's "Why I Am Not a Conservative," which first appeared as part of Hayek's Constitution of Liberty.
    Friedman is introduced by Ed Crane who notes that, while it is possible to argue about what economist had the most influence in the 20th century, no one can argue that anyone did more to spread the message of the free market system than Friedman.
  - Lee Edwards interivews Robert Schadler on 27 Feb 2003, 1 sound cassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0004837
  - Lee Edwards interviews Al Regnery on 16 Jul 2001, 1 sound cassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0004824
  - Lee Edwards interviews Annette Kirk on 23 Nov 1996, 1.0 sound microcassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0003431
    A conversation about the conservative movement of the twentieth century.
  - Lee Edwards interviews Brad Wilson on 5 Dec 2001, 1 sound cassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0004846
    This interview concerns the Intercollegiate Studies Institute (ISI).
  - Lee Edwards interviews Brigitte Krauss on 9 Jul 2001, 1 sound cassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0003988
    This discussion concerns her involvement with the ISI.
  - Lee Edwards interviews Charles Hoeflich on 11 Jul 2001, 1 sound cassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0003975
  - Lee Edwards interviews David Keene, et al, on 8 Apr 1997, 1 sound cassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0003984
    The interview focuses on the Goldwater campaign of 1964 and the following growth of the conservative movement. Included in this is how Keene and those around him became conservatives.
  - Lee Edwards interviews Dorothy Bageant on 3 Mar 1989, 1 sound cassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0003577
    Edwards interviews Dorothy Bageant about Dr. Walter H. Judd. While the conversation eventually briefly delves into questions of politics and policy, most of the conversation is about Judd as a person and employer. Though she believes it is difficult to sum him up in one word or phrase, she describes him as "scrupulously honest," "compassionate," "a good friend," and "very dedicated." Other topics of Judd as a person include his work ethic, skin cancer, and his proudest aspect was his MD degree, preferring to be called "Doctor" instead of "The Honorable."
    As an employer, topics she covers about Judd are: when she went to capitol hill and how she met Judd, his final campaign for office, how he encouraged his staff to learn things because he wanted his staff to know what they were doing, a walk-through of a typical day, speaking on the college circuit, oral histories, when she stopped working for him, and how the Hill is now compared to when she was there. She says the environment is completely different, especially in regards to the Congressmen's employees not knowing important things about their Congressman, such as committee assignments.
    On the policy side, she discusses Judd’s relationship with "big shots" such as Kennedy, Nixon, etc.; his papers; Nixon's offer to be on the ticket in 1960; and his relationship with Nixon in 1968.
    Another, unrelated, program is also on the tape. It is a Spanish translation of an English-language speech (audible in the background).
  - Lee Edwards interviews Ed Feulner on 22 Aug 2001, 1 sound cassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0003976
  - Lee Edwards interviews Frank Shakespeare on 14 Apr 1996, 1.0 sound microcassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0003429
    Interview about the Heritage Foundation, other think tanks, and the conservative movement of the twentieth century. The conversation is conducted in near whispers.
  - Lee Edwards interviews George Carey on 5 Jul 2001, 1 sound cassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0003590
    Edwards interviews George Carey about the ISI. The majority of the time is spent discussing various individuals affiliated with the ISI. Other topics include the name change of the ISI and how, over the years, the ISI has moved away from its libertarian bent towards a more general conservative big-tent organization; Carey's first interactions with the ISI; the Liberty Fund; and John Adams, Jefferson, Hamilton, and the founding fathers.
  - Lee Edwards interviews Gerhart Niemeyer on 25 Apr 1992, 1 sound cassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0004108
  - Lee Edwards interviews Harry Jaffa on 3 Aug 1993, 1 sound cassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0003977
    The main focus of this conversation is the 1964 campaign of Barry Goldwater, however other related topics are discussed as well.
  - Lee Edwards interviews Jerry Martin on 1 May 2002, 1.0 sound microcassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0003430
    An interview about the activities of the ISI. Martin stresses the success of the ISI in moving arguments about curriculum off campus. He singles out an issue of Georgetown removing Shakespeare from the curriculum.
  - Lee Edwards interviews John Lulves on 26 Feb 2001, 1 sound cassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0004107
    Concerns the ISI.
  - Lee Edwards interviews Larry Arnn and Milton Friedman in Aug 1996, 2.0 sound microcassettes (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0003432
    The interview with Larry Arnn is about the Heritage Foundation and other think tanks in the country. Arnn recounts how academia became politicized. The sound recording is not complete; the Friedman interview was likely taped over the Arnn interview.
    The interview with Milton Friedman is a discussion of think tanks in America from the 1940s to the present. A woman, probably Rose Friedman, is audible in the background helping Milton. Friedman recounts his experiences with various institutions and individuals thereof including, but not limited to, the Philadelphia Society, the Mont Perelin Society, the Intercollegiate Studies Institute, and the Heritage Foundation. The conversation touches on Barry Goldwater, Bill Clinton, Bob Dole, Jack Kemp, and Michael Dukakis. Friedman believes the most important think tanks are the Hoover Institution, Brookings, AEI, Heritage, Cato, Frazier, and NCPA.
  - Lee Edwards interviews Leonard Liggio on 31 Jul 1997, 1 sound cassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0004104
  - Lee Edwards interviews Leonard Liggio on 8 Aug 2001, 2.0 sound microcassettes (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0003378
    Lee Edwards interviews Leonard Liggio about the ISI. First they talk about its founder, Frank Chodorov as well as the conservative movement in the 1950s. People they talk about in the process are William F. Buckley, Jr., Robert Taft, and General MacArthur. Following Chodorov, the men then discuss Leonard Read, and E. Victor Milione.
    In the second half, the men discuss the ISI and its successes. Liggio believes there are three good things the ISI has been responsible for: champing the Austrian school of economics, defending Western civilization against its internal enemies, and emphasis on the classics and Christian foundation. Edwards then asks what stimulates students' minds. This is followed by both lamenting the state of education, that students do not know how undereducated they are.
    Third, they discuss Liggio's career in academia and miscellaneous aspects about the ISI.
  - Lee Edwards interviews Lew Lehrman on 13 Dec 1996, 1.0 sound microcassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0003472
    Edwards interviews Lew Lehrman about the Heritage Foundation and the conservative movement of the past fifty years.
    On the conservative movement, Lehrman argues an important point is the history really begins with Coolidge and not Robert Taft. He asks Edwards to consider of adding a sub-theme of his book to counteract Schlesinger. Lehrman argues Reagan was the most important conservative of the past fifty years, and "pray[s]" that no one tells Edwards that Goldwater was the most important. Tying the conservative movement history to that of think tanks, Lehrman argues that Goldwater is to the AEI as Reagan is to the Heritage Foundation. He believes the most important turning points of the movement are the most obvious ones, but also stresses the collapse of the Keynesian consensus. He argues that universities cannot respond to collapse of institutions and change their worldviews because of tenure.
    On the Heritage Foundation, Lehrman believes its work has been "very significant." He analyzes Heritage's takeover of AEI as the premier conservative think tank. Following, he stress the need for peaceful revolutions. He believes the board of think tanks should not be full of former heads of multinational corporations, comparing the two think tanks to illustrate his point. He points out that executives of established corporations cannot make big decisions that are very different from the interests of their corporations or without the approval of a board. He prefers a board made up of self-made (wo)men, arguing they can make major decisions very quickly and independently. He believes that think tanks still have a role to play, and constantly compares think tanks to the computer industry.
  - Lee Edwards interviews Loren Smith on 1 Apr 2002, 1.0 sound microcassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0003373
    This tape is an interview with Loren Smith concerning the ISI. The interview begins by Smith describing how he became a political conservative during his college days. He says that in 1960 he was a Kennedy supporter, especially views on tax cuts and the missile gap, yet he was mostly apolitical before college. His political awakening was a gradual growth. To illustrate the growth, he mentions several people that influenced or helped him along the way. This leads into a discussion of his post-college jobs.
  - Lee Edwards interviews M. Stanton Evans on 31 Oct 2001, 1 sound cassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0004840
  - Lee Edwards interviews Michael Novak on 15 Apr 1992, 1 sound cassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0004810
    Edwards interviews Novak about Goldwater and the conservative movement of the 20th century. Included in this is discussion of Ronald Reagan and the differences between Republicans and Democrats.
  - Lee Edwards interviews Michael Ratliff on 27 Feb 2001, 1 sound cassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0004816
  - Lee Edwards interviews Newt Gingrich on 13 Feb 1998, 1.0 sound microcassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0003376
    Edwards interviews Newt Gingrich about the Republican Party in the Twentieth Century. While Edwards was centering his interviews and book around a "big four" of Robert Taft, Barry Goldwater, Ronald Reagan, and Newt Gingrich. Gingrich counters that one cannot study the Republican Party in the twentieth century without analyzing Richard Nixon. Nixon was more influential for Gingrich than Taft. He goes on to explain why he favored both Reagan and Rockefeller over Nixon in 1968 and why he thought Nixon's approach was defeatist. Stating that he is standing on the shoulders of Reagan and Thatcher, they were not changing their party like he is changing the Republican Party to a less elitist organization. Gingrich comments on how he balances several roles (Speaker, leader of the Party, etc.), in the process explaining how Pete duPont was important to how Gingrich now works.
  - Lee Edwards interviews Newt Gingrich on 8 May 1998, 1.0 sound microcassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0003377
    The interview begins by Gingrich describing the political influences of his youth, how he came to his brand of Republicanism. Key influences he cites are a family leaning towards the Roosevelt wing of the Party, being in a Democratic state rifle with corruption, segregation and the civil rights act of 1964, and Ronald Reagan. He talks at length about Barry Goldwater and Richard Nixon, although he did not favor either, going just shy of using both as examples of what not to do. However, he feels his personal journey has been much closer to the journey of Nixon than Reagan. He thought Robert Taft was too abrupt with people.
    On being a leader, Gingrich says he read over 500 books as a graduate student because he thought some people ought to know how to lead. When describing his rise to power, he details how the coalitions he built were different than those before.
  - Lee Edwards interviews Peter Schramm on 7 Dec 2001, 1 sound cassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0004839
    This interview is about the Intercollegiate Studies Institute (ISI).
  - Lee Edwards interviews Robert Bartley on 12 Dec 1996, 1.0 sound microcassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0003433
    Poor sound quality. The interview was recorded at a very low level and Bartley's remarks are heavily masked by tape hiss.
  - Lee Edwards interviews Robert Riley on 30 Aug 2001, 1 sound cassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0004829
    This interview concerns the Intercollegiate Studies Institute.
  - Lee Edwards interviews Robert Ritchie on 30 Apr 2003, 1 sound cassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0004830
    This interview, conducted over the phone, concerns Ritchie's experiences with the Intercollegiate Studies Institute (ISI).
  - Lee Edwards interviews Robert Schadler on 6 Sep 2001, 1 sound cassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0004836
  - Lee Edwards interviews Ronald Reagan on 11 Sep 1979, 1 sound cassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0004819
  - Lee Edwards interviews Ronald Reagan on 14 Jun 1976, 1 sound cassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0004818
    Recorded in Los Angeles. Edwards inquires about Reagan's past, but also about what he expects to accomplish as President.
  - Lee Edwards interviews Russell Kirk on 29 May 1992, 1 sound cassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0003986
  - Lee Edwards interviews Spencer Masloff on 11 May 2001, 1 sound cassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0004112
    This interview concerns fund-raising for the ISI, but also contains segments related to the ISI's governance and leadership.
  - Lee Edwards interviews Steve Forbes on 3 Feb 1997, 1.0 sound microcassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0003471
    Edwards interviews Steve Forbes about the Heritage Foundation and the last fifty years of the conservative movement. Throughout the conversation, for both topics, Forbes delves into history to strengthen his arguments.
    Regarding the Heritage Foundation, Forbes sees the organization as fulfilling the need of the conservative movement for ideas. He argues that prior to Heritage, there was no one quickly providing them with arguing points, data, etc. on a consistent basis. He argues the GOP and conservatives did not have the intellectual ammunition to counteract the liberals. Forbes brings up political events of the late 1960s and 1970s to illustrate his point: creation of the Congressional Budget Office, Nixon taking the budget office out of the Treasury, and the 1968 election. The conversation also touches on Ed Feulner and Heritage's work on tax ideas.
    On the history of the conservative movement, Forbes calls Reagan the most important conservative of the last fifty years. He credits him with both the end of the cold war and the economic and technological boom of the 1980s. He says Reagan was what the GOP is not: optimistic and persuasive. He argues the party needs to control the political agenda better. This leads to an involved discussion on the political climate of the late 90s and what conservatives need to do better.
  - Lee Edwards interviews T. Kenneth Cribb, Jr. on 4 May 2003, 3.0 sound microcassettes (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0003374
    The conversation begins discussing Cribb's biographical information. Cribb talks about his parents and how they influenced his personality. Included in this are religion, music, and literature. While going chronologically, early on the discussion sidesteps into a discussion of President Reagan's humanity. Cribb jokingly uses his college experiences to illustrate why there ought to be rules because, slightly paraphrasing, "until the age of 25, every important decision a young person makes is based on ignorance." Shortly thereafter, the conversation delves into a discussion of American conservatism vs. libertarianism/the English Whig philosophy, mentioning names such as Mises, Rand, Buckley, Frum, and Rockwell. The third part moves into the effect the Federalist Society has on the government. Cribb believes the future Borks and Scalias will come from the Society. The discussion then moves on to the funding and goals of the ISI. The end of the conversation links literature and the humanities to the goals of the ISI, regarding education, and touches on how the libertarian, Cato-esque view is different from Cribb's.
  - Lee Edwards interviews Tom Roe on 13 Apr 1996, 1.0 sound microcassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0003428
    Edwards and Roe discuss the Heritage Foundation. Included is what it takes to get necessary personnel, Roe's biography, the Mont Pelerin Society, funding various projects at Heritage, publishing legislators' voting records, and how Heritage compares to other think tanks.
  - Lee Edwards interviews Vic Milione on 16 May 2001, 1 sound cassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0004806
  - Lee Edwards interviews Vic Milione on 29 Jul 2000, 1 sound cassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0004114
  - Lee Edwards interviews Victor Milione and Charles Hoeflick on 16 May 2001, 1 sound cassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0004807
  - Lee Edwards interviews Wayne Valis on 20 Oct 2001, 1 sound cassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0004845
  - Lee Edwards interviews William Campbell on 17 Nov 2001, 1 sound cassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0003589
    This interview concerns the ISI, Campbell's experiences at DePauw and in Minnesota, the programs of ISI, and the state of education in America. The sound quality of the recording indicates the interview was conducted over the phone.
  - Lee Edwards interviews William F. Buckley, Jr. on 11 Oct 2001, 1 sound cassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0003586
    Edwards interviews Buckley about people within the ISI.
  - Lee Edwards interviews William F. Buckley, Jr. on 12 Dec 1996, 1.0 sound microcassette (Box 330)
    Use copy reference number: 2010c14_a_0003477